Here we go.
What are you doing?
We're gonna be late.
Seven P's, honey:
Proper prior planning prevents
piss poor performance.
This isn't cool, Mom.
No, it is not cool.
But you know what is cool?
Your game was delayed until 7:00.
You got three hours to kill.
Why didn't you tell me?
I literally just told you.
Does dad know?
No.
I think he'll figure it out
when he gets to the field.
That's messed up.
Totally messed up.
Great, now I have more time to worry.
It's just a scrimmage, sweetheart.
Yeah, but I'm supposed to be on my way
to MVP stardom in college
like you were, so.
Yeah, well, I don't care
so much about the MVP stardom
as I do that free ride
so I don't have to pay
for that college tuition.
Speaking of, maybe you could help me
with that financial aid application.
Sweetie, I was just joking
about the scholarship.
It's okay if you don't get it.
Samantha, what is it?
Nothing.
Not nothing.
I want you to talk about this.
I know.
Whenever it is, you can say it.
I know!
Is someone out there?
I don't see anything.
- Sweetheart-
- Don't touch me!
You don't know how I
feel when I see its face.
Whose face?
Honey.
Baby, I need you to keep talking to me.
It's nothing.
Nothing, it's...
I can't play tonight.
Hey.
Fuck off!
You got a game to play.
Sweetie, I'm trying to
respect your privacy,
but you're scaring me.
I'm gonna assume you can't hear me
'cause you've got headphones on.
Okay, I'm coming in.
Oh, my God.
Ally, we're out of time.
I'm really sorry, but we have to move on.
We're turning over your patients
to someone else in the practice.
We really did try to work with you here.
Hey, Ally, it's Terry.
I know a therapist.
I know, I know, you're
probably rolling your eyes.
Why talk to another therapist?
Trust me, it was a lifesaver
for my sister when dad died.
And listen, I hope you don't mind,
but I relayed your contact info, so-
- It's not my time yet.
For the love of God.
Hi, Ally?
I'm Jan.
I heard that you weren't doing very well,
so I felt that I should come by in person.
Who are you?
I'm a psychologist.
Oh, okay, yeah.
Yeah, Terry mentioned you.
He said you were a lifesaver.
He didn't tell me you'd be so attentive.
Since I'm here, I
would just like to make sure
that you're not a danger to yourself.
And then, I'll be on my way.
Five minutes, that's all I need.
Sure, yeah.
No parent should
ever have to Bury her child.
I appreciate you coming,
it's a really lovely gesture.
I don't need your help.
I'll be fine.
Humor me for a moment.
And then I'll walk out that
door and never bother you again.
Sure.
Would you like to see
your daughter again?
Samantha, would you like to see her?
Because I'm sure she wants to see you.
Why would you say that to me?
You want to know why, why she did it?
It's perfectly natural.
She can tell you herself.
I think it's time that you left.
I am not going to beat around the bush.
As a therapist yourself, you
know there is a lot of bullshit
in this business.
Just hear me out.
This works.
I know because I've done it.
What is it?
It's tea.
It's been brewed with a
hallucinogenetic flower
called Datura stramonium.
And you want me to drink that?
Just a little bit.
I wouldn't see Sam,
I'd see a hallucination.
The psychedelic effects
are inconsequential.
It's what happens afterwards.
And what's that?
I was in your shoes once.
I drank the tea and
then I saw him, my boy.
My son who had been
murdered 20 years prior.
You have no idea how good
it felt to hug him again.
This is a way to know.
To see what Samantha saw,
to feel what she felt.
Are you ready to take that leap of faith?
Why would I believe any of this?
Because you're still listening.
There's a door to the other side.
This opens that door.
Give me call when you're
ready to walk through it.
Do you believe in ghosts?
That's an odd question.
I think it's odd that
I don't know the answer.
It's 95 degrees outside.
This afternoon I saw a kid in a scarf,
bundled up in winter clothing.
I thought that was odd.
No, I don't believe in ghosts.
I saw a therapist today.
She says she thinks she can help me.
Yeah?
You went outside?
Oh, no, she came here.
Why?
I don't know.
She's unconventional I guess.
I guess so.
If she's not in our network
we can't afford her.
Can you just humor me on this?
It's just me working now.
I can't keep doing this alone.
Well, we don't have a kid to
put through college anymore,
so there's that.
Is that supposed to be funny?
No.
I don't know why I said that.
I'm sorry.
How many handles of vodka
are in that kitchen right now?
Or pills in the bathroom?
Okay, you made your point.
Have I?
You want therapy?
Go outside.
That's not fair.
You can't keep living in this house,
hiding with her memory forever.
How is this so easy for you?
She's gone!
Okay?
That's it.
I'm sorry.
It's not easy for me.
Okay, hey, future Sam.
This is a recording on my song.
Let's hope I don't mess it up.
♪ You're in space ♪
♪ But I don't know where ♪
Samantha?
- Now?
- There's someone outside
in the backyard.
I'm calling the police.
Well, now, hang on a second.
Who's outside?
Someone wearing a mask.
I see it.
That's what's gonna take us to hell.
What?
Why would you say that?
I don't see anything.
Why would I say what?
- About us going to hell?
- What?
I never said that.
Jesus, Ally, it's like
you're on drugs or something.
No, I'm just spooked, that's all.
What are you doing?
- I'm gonna call 911.
- No!
If you call the cops
they'll be poking around
till 5:00 A.M. taking statements.
We both need our sleep.
So, what, I'm supposed to just let
a crazy person roam around my backyard?
No, it was nothing.
I just thought I saw Sam go downstairs.
And then I thought I saw
her go in the backyard.
You thought you saw Sam?
Clearly my imagination
is playing tricks on me.
I'm sorry.
Did you see anyone
in the backyard or not?
No.
Where are you going?
To take a look.
Why, why would you do that?
To make sure everything's okay, for you.
Well?
Just your imagination like you thought.
Look, if it makes you feel any better,
I once thought I saw
something creeping around
in the backyard too.
What was it?
I don't
know, the neighbor's cat.
Hello?
You said that for me to know why
I'd need to see what Samantha saw?
It's good to hear
from you again, Ally.
It is possible...
Did she tell you that?
That I needed to see these things?
Communicating with the other side
isn't as simple as picking up a phone.
We need to figure out what
Samantha is trying to say.
Is it possible I'm
already seeing what she saw?
Are you?
What did you see?
I saw...
Ally, did you drink the tea?
I took a sip.
What did you see?
I saw someone in
the backyard watching me.
And I know it's the same
thing that Samantha saw
because she drew a picture of it.
You took the leap.
Samantha is already trying to communicate.
So, what do I do now?
Talk to me.
We have a few chats.
I'll help you find her.
I don't know if we can afford that.
You don't need
to worry about that.
We'll try a couple of
sessions, no pressure.
I'll come to you.
I know your current situation.
It's best that you stay
inside, close to where she is;
Her energy.
Why would you do that?
I saw your story in the newspaper.
I sense so much sadness in you.
This is what I do.
This is who I am.
I don't know what to say.
Say when to be there.
Hey, that
therapist I told you about,
she's willing to come out
and do few sessions for free.
Really?
Why?
She wants to help.
You know anything about her?
Terry recommended her.
Terry from work?
Hm.
You don't think it's weird,
her coming out here and doing it for free?
I got a good feeling about her.
Why are you so high on this?
Lately, I am having trouble
seeing a purpose in anything.
Oh, babe, come on.
What about coaching softball again?
What does that have to do with anything?
I'm just saying, I
mean it might help you
find your purpose again.
No, no, like a valid purpose for me.
Nothing has purpose.
What about all those cards
in there from your patients?
Is there no purpose there?
I can't help them anymore.
- I'm a mess.
- Oh, come here.
I have no reason to be anymore.
What are you saying?
Hm?
Are you saying you'd rather be dead?
No.
Relax.
I'm not.
I'm just being dramatic.
I'm sorry to upset you.
Ally.
So, what do I do?
Strengthen the connection.
Why do you want to see her?
It's perfectly natural to want
to see our loved ones again.
You've shown me you'd do anything to share
another moment with her.
The way you live, torturing yourself.
Is that motivation driven by guilt?
Do you feel somehow responsible?
She had mood swings.
And at first I thought it
was normal teenage angst.
You talked to her about it?
I tried.
But it got bad really fast.
In the last two weeks, she was really off.
Up and down.
And sometimes she was really scared.
I just wish I had done something
the first time I saw it.
So, yeah, I do feel responsible.
Why don't you leave the house?
I can't.
Why?
Because I'm scared.
When I walk outside I can't breathe.
The idea of doing normal
things like driving in a car
or going to a friend's barbecue,
working at a job, it's terrifying.
Now we're getting somewhere.
Everything you just said
is completely normal.
No, it's nuts.
We are therapists.
Nuts are our specialty.
Samantha was an artist
and she kept a sketchbook.
I think I mentioned it on the phone.
I think she was drawing
pictures of the scary things
that she was seeing.
And I am seeing the same things.
May I see?
This one.
You saw this?
Right out there just like it's drawn.
Freaky stuff, right?
You saw all of these?
No, but the day Samantha
died she talked about a face,
and it really scared the hell out of her.
It's all very strange.
Reminds me a story I heard, long ago.
That's all for today.
Strengthen the connection.
Talk to me, Sam.
Someone made a mistake
and put this in my hand.
Get that outta here.
Show me your uh,
your beautiful artwork here.
Oh, you're a comedian, huh?
- Dad!
- Hi, baby.
- Hey.
- Be careful.
Look at how soft it is.
She's so cute, I don't
know where she gets it from.
Aw.
Ladies and gentlemen, what we have here
is a grill full of hamburgers.
There we go, that's
that famous Larkin wit.
- Soon to be cheeseburgers.
- Mm.
Be careful, you don't
want me to bust out my lines
from the wedding now, do you?
Oh, please.
You know I love your "love
is baseball" metaphors.
Blah!
Don't.
Get the camera outta my face.
Samantha, can you come over here?
Can I take a video of you?
- Yeah.
- Come here.
All right, pause right there.
Can you say, "I'm four years old."
I'm four years old.
And I'm almost a grownup.
I'm almost a grownup.
And I can take care of myself.
I can take care of myself.
That's good.
Hi.
How'd you get in here?
Are you lost?
You're not in trouble.
It's okay.
I just need you to talk to me.
Were you watching home
movies in Sam's room?
No.
Why?
There was a tape in the VCR.
So maybe she was watching it?
There's nothing we coulda done, right?
Right.
Must've been a warning sign.
I just wish I had seen it.
So maybe you missed it.
Nothing we can do about it now.
So that means I'm terrible at my job.
A little reassurance would be nice.
What do you want me to say?
She saw things that weren't real.
That's your fault?
I shoulda done something.
What about you the other night?
There's no purpose in anything.
Is that a warning sign?
Should I be doing something?
You think I'm ridiculous?
No, no, I never said that.
I told you years ago I
would never use that word
to describe someone.
We're human beings.
We do what we do.
I don't know what to say sometimes.
You had a few words worth moments.
Nah, I just think you like
my old cheese ball lines.
Remember what you said
to me on our wedding day?
Oh, yeah.
Was it uh, "I've always
swung for the fences",
but with you I actually connected."
Wow, no stumping you.
Yeah.
Never got that cabin.
You have to remind me?
Cool mountain air.
We once said that was
the epitome of happiness.
Think it's too late for us?
I hope not.
Remember that dance at our wedding?
And I did this and this.
Good moves, Mr. Larkin.
How much longer do you think
he'll humor your reclusiveness?
As long as it takes.
How long will that be?
I don't know.
But he's been very supportive
and he still cares.
He goes to work everyday,
takes on all the financial
burden without complaint.
What are you trying to say?
Are you sure he's at
work the whole time?
You think he's cheating on me?
It's just a thought.
Here's a thought, Jan.
Why don't you blow it out your ass?
Touche.
There's something I've been
wanting to talk to you about.
Samantha's sketchbook.
Yeah.
I was gonna actually bring that up.
It seemed like it kind of upset you.
I was hesitant to talk about it.
I heard a ghost story once.
About a scarred face with no eyes.
You've heard the saying,
"The eyes are the window to the soul?"
Mm hm.
Many years ago I was a
missionary in Botswana.
The locals told us about the Ubuso.
A malevolent shape shifting
spirit from an ancient world.
On its own it was simply
the air you breathe,
but to its victims it was
the embodiment of insanity.
The Ubuso had no eyes in its true form.
It would steal eyes from humans
and use their eyes to see into their soul.
To find their will to live and destroy it.
The Ubuso fed on misery.
So, if it would see into your soul,
it could see your fears,
your sadness, your pain.
How did they stop it?
They didn't.
In the Zulu language,
Ubuso means many faces.
The spirit had the ability
to take on any form.
That's how it got its name.
Once it burrowed deep
into a person's psyche,
it could manipulate reality.
Once that happened, madness set in.
And led to suicide.
The spirit was a parasite,
so afterward it moved on to another.
And this is what happened to Samantha?
And me?
No, it's just a story.
The drawings are just a wild coincidence.
So, why are you telling me this?
Stories are created to
explain the unexplainable.
You want to know why.
I believe Samantha is trying to show you.
So I can understand
what she went through.
Yes.
We need to continue to
build the connection.
Keep drinking the tea.
The door's already open,
you don't need to do that.
You're not still drinking it are you?
What I've seen, it's not just vision.
It's trying to communicate with me.
How do you mean?
I saw a boy in Samantha's room.
He had no mouth.
And I saw him in Samantha's sketchbook.
Samantha's breaking through.
He wrote on the wall,
"Give me your voice."
So it's gotta be connected.
Don't think so much.
When you see Samantha,
it will all make sense.
Seems like I'm gonna
have to see the face
with no eyes before that happens.
Let's hope you don't.
Hey.
Can I talk to you about something?
Sure.
Sit down.
We were just kids when Sam was born.
We talked about having another
baby when things settled down
and we finished school.
We never had that conversation.
Yeah.
Life happened.
You wanna have that conversation now?
Why?
Why not?
Why now?
- You wanna replace Sam?
- No.
No, no, baby, no, no, I did not say that.
Please don't put words in my mouth.
So, why then?
I'm just merely bringing up the fact
that we never had the conversation.
- We're not ready for that.
- We're not ready?
Okay, I'm not ready.
Don't do that, don't
blow me off every time
I try to have a real
conversation about something.
You always storm off.
It's ridiculous.
I'm ridiculous?
No, I said this is
ridiculous, this situation.
I already told you I would
never call you ridiculous.
Mom?
Hello?
Samantha?
Are you trying to tell me something?
If you are, I don't understand.
Mom?
Why didn't you stop me?
Look what I did.
This isn't real.
Come outside, Mom.
The weather's fantastic.
Healing is not without pain.
We have to look at ourselves in the mirror
and see the truth.
I've seen plenty of things.
There's no truth to any of it.
It's part of the process.
I can barely will myself
out of bed every morning,
and then you came along and
everything's the same except
for now I don't know what's real.
Mom?
Do you hear that?
You're still
drinking the tea aren't you?
I don't see anything without it.
That's not how it works.
Dump it down the drain.
It's done, you can already
see the other side.
Is that so?
How many awful things
did you have to endure
before you got to see your son?
Patience.
You told me to take a leap of faith.
I did.
When do I get to see my daughter?
You're not there yet.
When then?
When I've gone completely insane?
Insane people don't have the wherewithal
to acknowledge their own insanity.
I saw my daughter's dead body
come alive in the bath tub.
What does that do to help me
understand her or her illness?
Ally, it's not that simple.
Perhaps she's waiting for
you to sort something out
with her father.
Like what?
Do you know where
Michael stands with you?
With your family?
He wants to have a baby.
Really?
A replacement for Samantha?
No, not like that.
- How old are you?
- 36.
Why?
You don't have much time left.
For what?
To have a family again.
Time is limited for Michael as well.
If this is what he wants,
he might consider starting
a family with someone else.
On what planet would
that be considered helpful?
It's part of the process.
Get out.
Ally.
I don't like the way I
feel when I'm with you.
You knew that I would
push you to talk, remember?
I've decided that
drugs and ghost stories
are not good therapy.
I don't mean to offend.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Michael, are you home?
Jesus, kid, enough with the jump scares.
What do you want?
Why do you torture me with memories?
Samantha?
Mornin'.
Am I dreaming?
No.
It's really me.
I miss you so much.
Mom, you need to listen to me.
What is it?
You're going down the same path.
You're seeing what I saw.
But you've yet to see the worst.
It never stops.
I'm so sorry, I didn't know.
But you did know.
I was sick.
I've wished so many
times I could stop you
from going in that garage.
Stop making excuses.
So you do blame me?
Don't you wanna make things right?
I don't understand.
You've become a shut-in.
Your career, your marriage,
your life is a joke.
What?
Why would you say that?
You've nailed yourself to a cross.
Why?
To prove you were a good mother?
You don't think I was a good mother?
But you can make things right.
End it.
Give me your eyes.
Your eyes.
Give 'em to me.
You're not real.
Oh, am I real now?
Some of 'em slit their wrists.
Some of 'em put a gun in their mouth.
You'll cut out your eyes.
Just like she did.
Just like this.
Ally, what's wrong?
What happened?
What happened, babe?
You just walked into the
kitchen and started screaming.
What the hell's going on?
- I thought I saw Sam.
- You, whoa, whoa, whoa.
But it wasn't her.
You thought you saw Sam again?
That's it, I'm taking you to a doctor.
No.
I'm not gonna sit back and watch you
keep doing this to yourself.
If you won't leave the house,
I'm gonna call one and bring one here.
I'm sorry, but this is nonnegotiable.
Physically you're fine.
- It's just stress.
- That's it?
With a traumatic event like
you've both been through,
it's perfectly natural.
Are you taking any medications currently?
I take a Valium sometimes.
- You take that with alcohol?
- She hasn't had anything
to drink today.
Michael, this is
embarrassing enough as it is.
He doesn't need to be here.
Well, I brought some
samples 'cause I thought
they'd come in handy.
And I will write you a prescription.
Take one of those once a day.
Only those, no other pills, no booze.
What is it?
It's a strong sedative.
- It'll keep you calm.
- And then what?
The elephant in the room, the visions.
I need to run some tests.
An MRI is a good start.
- I don't need an MRI.
- Ally.
I'm not stressed.
I'm not crazy.
I'm not having a nervous breakdown.
It was all a hallucination.
I've been drinking a
tea that had this stuff
called Datura in it.
Datura?
Well, that's Jimsonweed.
I don't know, sure.
Okay, can somebody fill me in?
It's a drug that makes you see things.
It's poison.
We may need to get her to the ER.
No, I'm not on it anymore.
I swear.
It will kill you.
You know that, right?
How much?
How much what?
Would kill you?
Any amount, the smallest amount.
Please do not take this lightly.
This is not magic mushrooms
where you get a case
of the giggles while
watching the carpet breathe.
Datura is something else entirely.
It's having conversations
with people that don't exist.
Assuming you don't die,
it's self-induced insanity.
Ally.
The therapist, she gave it to me.
The lady making the house calls?
I knew something was up with that quack.
Do you still have this drug?
Yeah.
It is all a stupid mistake.
I'm getting it right now.
Please take it out of my hands.
This is all a disaster, really.
The therapist that gave it to you,
do you have their contact information?
Yes, I'll get you her card.
No wonder she'd feel the effects
if it was a drug.
Under the influence it's impossible
to decern fantasy from reality.
Your daughter, she saw things too?
Yeah, but it wasn't drugs.
We had an autopsy done.
Does mental illness run in the family?
- No.
- Schizophrenia?
No, no, nothing like that.
Um, but listen, this has been
going on for a while now.
She won't leave the house, ever.
I think she's losing it.
I think she's causing me to lose it, too.
I can't find her card.
Her name is Janice Rollins,
I'll find her number later.
It's fine, I can
probably dig up some info
just based on the name.
Why would you do something like this?
You're in the medical field,
you should know better.
She told me I could
see my daughter again.
What does that mean?
Sam's ghost, I could talk
to her on the other side.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
What's in this stuff?
It's strong, like I said.
Just get some rest.
You need to get this
stuff outta your system.
Let me borrow you for a second.
You gotta do something.
Yeah, I'm gonna do some tests for me,
we'll get this sorted out.
What kinda stuff are you worried about?
Ally?
How long have I been asleep?
18 hours.
It's okay, you needed it.
The doctor said that stuff can
stay in your system for days.
Why aren't you at work?
I'm taking a few days off.
Why?
I wanna keep an eye on you.
Sweetie, you don't need to do that.
I know I've been a mess, but
I don't need a babysitter.
It's okay.
I wanna be here.
That was pretty scary shit, you know?
I'm gonna make it right, I promise.
I shoulda known something
was up the other day
when you thought you saw
someone in the backyard.
I mean, why would you
do something like that?
Take a drug from a complete stranger?
I wanted to see Samantha so
bad, I had nothing to lose.
I was ready to die.
So the other night when you said
you were just being
dramatic, that was a lie?
Yeah.
I don't know what else to say.
This is my wake-up call, sweetie.
I'm so embarrassed.
I drank poison from a stranger.
I've been a walking disaster.
It's not fair to you.
And a string of bad decisions.
I wanna do better.
I'll make it right.
How?
I don't know.
I feel like everything's gonna be okay.
Once you hit rock bottom,
there's only one way to go.
I've missed you.
This is Jan Rollins.
Leave me a message.
Hey, Jan, what you did, I need answers.
Feeling all right?
What are you doing?
Strategy.
I'm gonna hit up all my old patients.
Why?
I'm gonna start my own practice.
Are you sure you're ready
for something like that?
Probably not.
But I'll tell myself I am
as many times as I need to
until I believe it.
I'm too good to work for
a healthcare network.
I should've broken off
on my own years ago,
but I was just too scared.
That's great.
I got in this business to help people,
and I wanna get that back.
I don't wanna get ahead of myself,
but I might take your suggestion
and start coaching softball again.
Wow.
No booze?
Baby steps.
Baby steps would be
going outside for once.
What's with you tonight?
- Hello?
- Hi, Kate.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry it's been a while.
It is so good to hear from you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, no, I'm good.
I remembered that postcard you gave me
with the mountain scape.
It really meant a lot to me, so thank you.
Are you kidding?
- Anytime.
- Thank you.
Well, I'm gonna be starting
my own practice soon,
and if you wanted to continue
our sessions we could do that.
Maybe in a few weeks or
months even, when I'm settled.
Really?
Congrats, that's so exciting.
Of course.
I speak the world of you.
Thank you.
I'm to the moon, Kate.
I guess we'll be in touch.
Okay, bye.
- Hello?
- Terry.
Ally?
I've been meaning to call you.
That therapist you recommended,
she's a real piece of work.
Did she give hallucinogenetic
drugs to your sister too?
- I'm sorry, what?
- How could you recommend
someone like that?
I'm a bit lost right now.
What, what do you mean?
You called, you left me
a message about a therapist
you called a miracle worker.
You don't remember that.
Yeah, yeah, he's great.
- Dave Myer.
- He?
Yes, is that a problem?
Who is Jan Rollins?
I'm sorry, I don't
know anybody by that name.
Ally, what the hell's going on?
Is everything okay?
I just got off the phone with Terry.
Can this wait?
No, actually, it can't!
Ally, I just wanna be left alone.
What the hell is with you?
Hey.
You're awake.
Come on, what's the matter?
I had a terrible dream.
What happened?
I feel stupid.
Well, after everything I
think you get a few passes.
This thing was chasing
me through the woods.
At lightning speeds.
It was like I was in slow motion.
Finally get to a house,
to safety, to the door...
And my foot hits a rock and I fall.
I'm sure it's just a dream.
No, no, no.
This was so real, it was different.
This face, it's the
most burned and scarred,
and there were no eyes.
Just burns all over.
I wanna show you something.
Where are you going?
Is that what you saw?
I got spooked from a bad dream.
You don't have to make fun of me.
I'm not making fun of you.
Sam saw that.
Sam drew that.
Are you on that drug again?
No, of course not.
Then why'd you bring me this?
Because you saw it in your dream!
Does what I described
sound like a penguin?
No, the face with no eyes.
Or a Pegasus with rainbow hair?
Or puppies?
There are pictures
of the face with no eyes
and scars and-
- That's what you thought you saw!
You saw it in your dream.
I must've heard you describe it.
It was just a bad dream.
Hello?
Mrs. Larkin.
Hello, it's Dr. Harris.
Is your husband in?
No, he's out.
Can I help you?
How are you feeling?
Fine.
Are you taking
that sedative I prescribed?
Um, not since the first day.
I haven't needed it.
Oh, great.
Have you had any more hallucinations?
No, it was just the tea.
That's what I'm calling about.
We did extensive tests on
the liquid in that bottle,
and there was no Datura present.
In fact, there was nothing
out of the ordinary about it.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
It was iced tea.
Just iced tea.
That's impossible.
- Mrs.
- Larkin, when I said before
that we should run-
Give me your eyes.
I think she's
causing me to lose it too.
So you are real!
This is what you want?
No, it's this, isn't it?
You want my eyes?
Come and cut 'em out yourself!
Ally, listen to me.
The Ubuso, it's real and
it's gone after Michael.
I thought we could beat
it before it got to you,
but it's moved on.
Time is of the essence.
You lied to me.
You let me think that
you were Terry's guy.
I trusted you.
I had to.
You would've brushed off
the whole idea if I hadn't.
Leap of faith, remember?
I needed you to believe.
- Is your name even Jan?
- No.
What I do, I have to take precautions.
Listen, you and your
husband are in danger.
Everything you say is bullshit.
Why would I believe you?
Because you need my help.
What was the last thing
that Samantha said to you?
Nothing good, was it?
Fuck off.
That's the last thing she said to me.
Start making sense.
In every case of the
Ubuso, the last victim tries
to commune with the living to warn them.
To tell them how to stop it.
That's why it is so
important to get to Samantha
before it's too late.
I've already seen her.
Her corpse crawling out of a body bag.
A girl taunting me to cut my eyes out.
That's not my daughter.
Of course it isn't.
It's using her likeness
to drive you insane.
Until you kill yourself.
That's what it wants.
How do you know all this?
I've been following it
since my missionary days.
I've followed it all over the world.
Why am I seeing a boy with no mouth?
And why was there a man wearing
a doll's mask in my backyard?
Ubuso, faces, a shape shifter.
All illusions to scare you.
Why haven't I seen the eyeless face?
We need to talk to Samantha.
Where's Michael?
Running errands, why?
- We need him.
- We do?
Clearly it's gotten to him.
He's already seen it, hasn't he?
What do I have to do?
I need you to gather some items.
What now?
Just wait.
Michael, before you get angry.
Just let me explain.
The thing you saw in
your dream with no eyes,
it's what killed Samantha.
And this is how we're gonna stop it.
That's Jan, she's the
therapist I've been talking to,
but she can help us.
And I know you're thinking,
"What the hell, Ally?
This is crazy."
And I know, believe me.
Michael?
Wake me up.
What?
Wake me up from this dream.
This can't be real.
Tell me it's not real.
What's the matter with you?
That is the thing from my dream.
What do you see?
Michael?
It has no eyes, yet it stares at me.
Why!
You.
Why do you have eyes?
Why don't I see what he sees?
Leave him alone!
You want me?
Come and get me!
Show me what you really look like!
You'll see soon enough.
Come on outside, Ally.
The weather is fantastic.
Hey, take this.
It's from Dr. Harris.
Let's just calm down.
We'll figure all this out.
It's okay.
♪ I dream of earthquakes and you ♪
♪ I dream of a world- ♪
I wanted to ask you more
about the things I see.
I want to ask you something too.
Last time we talked about whether or not
your mother really loved you.
Perhaps she was faking it.
Do you still feel that way?
But I need to understand
what's happening to me.
And I want to talk
to you about your mother.
She's not a good mother, is she?
I don't like the
way I feel when I'm with you.
We're done.
But you need my help
or else the Ubuso will get you.
It's real?
I thought it was just a ghost story.
Where did you
get that bottle of water
you're drinking right now?
You gave it to me.
You seem pretty sure about that.
But actually you got it
out of the fridge yourself.
The Ubuso can manipulate
reality anyway it sees fit.
It can answer phones and ring doorbells.
It can take the form of
your friends and loved ones.
It can have the walls close in on you.
Make you afraid to walk outside.
Drive you insane.
It is your God now.
It can even make this tape
you're listening to, Ally.
We don't know, it could
chase us in our dreams.
Can't kill ourselves if we're asleep.
I'm sorry.
Did you do this?
It's so you wouldn't stop me.
Michael, cut it out.
I see it now.
Both of us.
We're crazy just like Sam.
What are you doing?
Why do you have this?
Where'd you even get it from?
Nothing good comes from having this.
Michael, it's nothing.
Don't listen to it.
It wants us to die.
Don't you understand?
I tried so hard to be strong.
It was never easy for me.
Why can't you see that?
Michael, we're doing fine.
Just fine.
Don't do this.
- We can get through this.
- No.
You hear me?
All we can do is end it.
Don't say that.
Michael, snap out of it.
All I ever wanted was for
you to give me your love.
Michael.
No!
Michael!
Michael, say something.
Michael, say something!
Oh, Michael.
Take me.
Take me, take me, take me.
Give him back.
Take me, take me.
Michael.
You took my family.
You took my family!
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
You took my family!
Pathetic.
After everything, you'd still
rather stay in here with me
than go out there.
I told you before.
You want my eyes?
Come and cut 'em out yourself.
Don't you know?
I am your God now.
You.
I thought you were one of the same.
Fuck off!
You mock me with her words?
Did you hear me?
That's right.
Look at me when I'm talking
to you, you fuckin' bitch.
I already told you, come
cut them out yourself.
You're against her?
You're scared.
Who are you?
Enough!
He can't help you now.
This is where you die,
just like your daughter.
None of this is real.
Don't you recognize yourself?
This is a trick.
Yes, because
you're imagining it.
You're the voice inside
my head that won't let go.
I see the most terrible things
because you believe in them.
There is no evil spirit.
You've trapped us in a nightmare.
You need to finally let go.
Free us.
It's time to wake up!
How?
Give me your fucking eyes!
Mom, help me.
Help me!
Why didn't you help me?
You're not my daughter.
- You're not real.
- Real?
You'll never know what's real.
Never again.
Don't you want it to stop?
No!
Easy, Ally.
What are you doing?
Stop it.
I know it's you.
Yeah, it's me, your husband.
I saw you die.
What are you talking about?
I'm standing right here.
Put the bat down.
Look, this whole thing's been
rough on both of us, okay?
Sweetheart.
Do you remember what you
said to me at our wedding?
Of course.
That you're batting
1,000 when you're with me.
I'm batting 1,000 when I'm with you.
I remember it like it was yesterday.
It is you.
Come here.
I'm ridiculous, I'm sorry.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay, you can
tell me I'm ridiculous.
You're ridiculous.
I can't fight anymore.
You don't have to.
Everything you're feeling
right now, just accept it.
Let it flow through you.
This is what you want?
I love you.
I told her how you steal eyes.
What?
Memories are powerful things.
Find a good one, a symbol, and
suddenly an ordinary object
can be used as a weapon to
destroy the Ubuso forever.
Did you forget that I
could change faces too?
But that doesn't happen.
But it does.
Sometimes I get their voice,
but sometimes they listen.
And I get their ears, too.
She knows your secret now.
You took my family.
I won't let you take anyone else.
I have purpose.
Seven P's, honey:
Proper prior planning prevents
piss poor performance.
Samantha?
No, I met her though.
She's okay.
And she wants you to be okay.
You'll meet her again one day.
It's not your time yet.
♪ I dream of earthquakes and you ♪
♪ I dream of a world I can understand ♪
♪ And I miss you ♪
♪ And I thought I saw you ♪
Here we go.
♪ Thought I saw a ghost ♪